Contact

nelvina777@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-mary-hanna-a8276884 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Critical Care

BLS

Nursing

Languages

Arabic

Spanish

Dr. Mary Hanna

Rn, PhD, CEN at Mary N. Hanna

Ludington, Michigan

Summary

Creating a vision for all for the purpose of a new tomorrow in a world that transforms healing. Starting with the healers and extending within a global community. ~Healing the Healers~

My vision for the world is that family units stay together and share love, peace, and happiness. Families are creating moments in time living in a universe without war and conflict.

working in direct patient care, teaching, mentoring while conducting original research

My passions include teaching, precepting and mentoring nurses and allied health forces. I have practiced emergency nursing at all levels of trauma from rural settings to level one trauma centers affiliated with State Universities. I have taught clinical nursing in community college and at University level that allows me to stay involved in direct patient care and in a mentorship role. Travel nursing provides the freedom to practice and learn a variety of practice procedures from different perspectives. I also mentor graduate and doctorate level students. I obtained my PhD in the philosophy of nursing in 2020 completing a qualitative descriptive phenomenological study on MORAL DISTRESS EXPERIENCED BY LEVEL ONE TRAUMA NURSES: A PHENOMENOLOGICAL STUDY. My interest is in a combination of direct patient care, teaching, and research. I am working at being the best that I can be while serving in the profession that has helped to define who I am, as a professional nurse. < script type="text/javascript" src="https://platform.linkedin.com/badges/js/ profile.js" async defer></script>

Experience

Mary N. Hanna Rn, PhD, CEN April 2020 - Present (4 months) Global Trinity Health (HQ Michigan)
Travel RN EPIC conversion ER/Trauma
October 2019 - Present (10 months)

Muskegon, Michigan

Stonybrook Southampton Hospital RN,BSN,MSN/eD,PhDc,CEN June 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months) Southampton, New York

Fastaff Travel Nursing RN,BSN,MSN/eD,PhDc,CEN October 2016 - Present (3 years 10 months) USA

Emergency /Trauma

AMN Healthcare Travel RN October 2016 - Present (3 years 10 months) Michigan

My Aim is the optimal experience for both patients and nurses

Michigan State University
Clinical Instructor
August 2011 - February 2017 (5 years 7 months)
Clinical Nursing Instructor for Undergraduate program at MSU CON

Sparrow Health System
Assistant Department Manager
December 2011 - August 2016 (4 years 9 months)
Lansing, Michigan Area

Emergency Department/Level One Trauma Center affiliated with Michigan State University

Sparrow RN,MSN/EDU, CEN January 2011 - August 2016 (5 years 8 months) 1215 Michigan Ave, Lansing

Level-one Trauma Center at large Urban Teaching Hospital

Spectrum Health Ludington Hospital

Page 2 of 4

Emergency Charge and Staff RN

January 2007 - January 2010 (3 years 1 month)

Acute access community rural hospital in north western Michigan

Mercy Health (formerly Mercy Health Partners)

Registered Nurse

July 2004 - January 2007 (2 years 7 months)

Charge nurse, staff nurse preceptor for new nurses to emergency department, staff nurse level two trauma

Mercey health partners hackley muskegon

RN

2004 - 2007 (3 years)

Muskegon, Michigan

Charge nurse

Coordinate allied health and nursing level two trauma Ctr

The Christ Hospital Health Network

18 years 1 month

Registered nurse

January 1986 - January 2004 (18 years 1 month)

Assistant Manager of Emergency services department, charge nurse and preceptor for new nurses

RN

1986 - 2004 (18 years)

Jersey City, New Jersey

Asst dept manager/ charge nurse staff nurse

Direct pt care to directing pt care

In pt psych/ detox, surgical nursing, step down telemetry, ortho, ICU/ ccu, med/ surg progressively to emergency nursing

Ogden avenue health center

Lpn

1985 - 1986 (1 year)

Jersey City, New Jersey

Charge nurse 40 pt unit geriatric center

Coordinate compassionate care with ancillary team nurses, aids, recreational therapists, and patients / families

Education

University of Phoenix

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Nursing · (2012 - 2020)

New Jersey City University

BSN, Nursing Science · (2000 - 2003)

Christ Hosptial School of Nursing

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1997 - 1999)

Jersey City Board of Education

License Practical Nurse, Nursing · (1985 - 1986)